Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another great lesson and this time we're going to be shopping.
今天我们为大家带来另一节精彩的课程，这次我们要去购物。
That's right.
没错。
Actually a lot of our users asked for some lessons about shopping, right?
实际上，很多用户都要求我们做一些关于购物的课程，对吧？
Exactly.
确实。
And I think one of the most important things when you go shopping is to get a good price.
我觉得购物时最重要的事情之一就是拿到一个好价钱。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to be teaching you how to bargain.
所以我们要教大家如何讨价还价。
So Marco, you just mentioned a really great word.
Marco，你刚才提到了一个很好的词。
Let's look at it in Vocabulary Preview.
我们来看看词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to preview the word bargain today.
今天我们预览一下bargain这个词。
Bargain.
Bargain。
Now this is an interesting word because it's a verb and a noun.
这个词很有趣，因为它既是动词又是名词。
That's right.
没错。
So a bargain is a good price, right?
所以bargain作为名词是指好价钱，对吧？
Okay.
嗯。
So a bargain is a good price.
所以bargain就是好价钱。
Yeah.
是的。
This t-shirt was a bargain.
这件T恤很划算。
I only paid a dollar for it.
我只花了一美元买的。
Okay.
嗯。
So that is a bargain.
那就是bargain。
Yes.
是的。
But to bargain as a verb?
那bargain作为动词呢？
To try and get a good price.
试图得到一个好价钱。
So it's very similar to negotiate.
所以它和negotiate很相似。
Yeah.
是的。
So I would say, it costs a hundred dollars.
比如我会说，这个要一百美元。
And then I would say maybe, no, I'll give you 50.
然后我可能会说，不，我给你50。
75.
75。
And then I'll say 60.
然后我说60。
Et cetera, et cetera.
等等等等。
And that's to bargain, right?
那就是讨价还价，对吧？
Yep.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So we're going to be bargaining.
所以我们要讨价还价了。
Let's listen to the dialogue for the first time as we have a woman bargaining in a store,
让我们第一次听对话，一位女士在商店里讨价还价，
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Hello, may I help you?
你好，有什么需要帮忙的吗？
Yeah, this dress is really nice.
嗯，这件裙子真好看。
How much is it?
多少钱？
That one is $150.
那件是150美元。
$150?
150美元？
What about this other one over here?
那这边这件呢？
That's 140.
那件是140美元。
That's a bit out of my price range.
这有点超出我的预算了。
Can you give me a better deal?
能给我便宜点吗？
This is an exclusive design by Da Marco.
这是达·马可的独家设计。
What's a bargain at that price?
这个价格已经很划算了。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不太确定。
I think I'll shop around.
我想再去别家看看。
Okay, okay.
好吧，好吧。
How about $100?
100美元怎么样？
That's still more than I wanted to spend.
那还是比我预想的花费要多。
What if I take both dresses?
如果我两件都要呢？
Okay, I can give you a special discount just because you seem like a nice person.
好吧，我可以给你一个特别折扣，因为你看起来人不错。
190 for both.
两件190美元。
I don't know.
我不太确定。
It's still a bit pricey.
还是有点贵。
Thanks anyway.
不过还是谢谢你。
Okay, my final price, $100 for both.
好吧，我的最终价，两件100美元。
There's two for the price of one and that's my last offer.
买一送一，这是我最后的报价了。
Great.
太好了。
You caused a deal.
你成交了。
All right.
好的。
That was some good bargaining skills right there.
这讨价还价的技巧真不错。
Yeah, and you know what?
是啊，你知道吗？
She used a lot of good language to get a cheaper price, didn't she?
她用了很多好的表达来拿到更便宜的价格，对吧？
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
That was good.
真不错。
So, let's take a look at this language in Language Takeaway.
那么，我们来看看语言点部分中的这些表达。
Language Takeaway.
语言点。
Okay, the first word we have in Language Takeaway today, price range.
好的，今天语言点的第一个词是：价格范围。
Price range.
价格范围。
What does that mean exactly?
那到底是什么意思？
So, price range is the minimum and the maximum that you're willing to spend for a thing that
所以，价格范围就是你愿意为想买的东西支付的最低和最高金额。
you want to buy.
没错。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So, in the dialogue we heard, it's out of my price range.
在对话中我们听到，这超出了我的价格范围。
It's more than I can spend.
这超出了我的承受能力。
More than I could spend.
超出了我的承受能力。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, let's look at her next word, shop around.
好的，我们来看看她的下一个词，货比三家。
Shop around.
货比三家。
So, she said, I think I'll shop around.
她说，我想我会货比三家。
Right.
对。
So, she wants to check in a few other stores to see if there's a better price.
她想看看其他几家店有没有更便宜的价格。
If I shop around, I'm going and trying to compare prices maybe.
如果我货比三家，我会去比较价格。
Exactly.
没错。
This is a really good shopping technique.
这是一个很好的购物技巧。
Yeah, it is.
是的，确实如此。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay, and let's look at her last word, pricey.
好的，我们来看看她的最后一个词，昂贵的。
Pricey.
昂贵的。
So, something that's pricey is...
所以，说某样东西很贵就是……
Expensive.
昂贵的。
Yep.
是的。
This is a more sort of informal way of saying expensive.
这是一种比较非正式的说法，表示昂贵。
Exactly.
没错。
So, instead of saying, wow, that car is really expensive.
所以，与其说，哇，那辆车真贵。
It's really pricey.
它真的很贵。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay, let's listen to our dialogue for the second time and it's going to be slowed down
好的，让我们再听一遍对话，这次会慢一点。
a bit.
慢一点。
So, you'll understand some of these great words a little bit better.
这样你就能更好地理解这些好词了。
Hello, may I help you?
你好，有什么需要帮忙的吗？
Yeah, this dress is really nice.
嗯，这件裙子真好看。
How much is it?
多少钱？
That one is $150.
那件150美元。
$150?
150美元？
What about this other one over here?
那这边这件呢？
That's $140.
那件140美元。
Hmm, that's a bit out of my price range.
嗯，有点超出我的预算了。
Can you give me a better deal?
能给我便宜点吗？
This is an exclusive design by Da Marco.
这是达·马可的独家设计。
It's a bargain at that price.
这个价格已经很划算了。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不太确定。
I think I'll shop around.
我想再逛逛。
Okay, okay.
好吧好吧。
How about $100?
100美元怎么样？
That's still more than I wanted to spend.
那还是比我预想的花费多。
What if I take both dresses?
如果我两条裙子都要呢？
Okay.
好吧。
I can give you a special discount just because you seem like a nice person.
我可以给你一个特别折扣，因为你看起来人不错。
$190 for both.
两条一共190美元。
I don't know.
我不太确定。
It's still a bit pricey.
还是有点贵。
Thanks anyway.
不过还是谢谢。
Okay, my final price.
好吧，我的最终价。
$100 for both.
两条100美元。
That's two for the price of one.
这相当于买一送一。
That's my last offer.
这是我的最后报价。
Great.
太好了。
You've got a deal.
成交。
So we've covered the language in this dialogue.
我们已经讲解了这段对话中的语言点。
Now let's take a look at some of the phrases in Putting It Together.
现在让我们看看“融会贯通”部分的一些短语。
Putting It Together.
融会贯通。
So Marco, in this dialogue, there's a lot of really useful phrases to help you get a
马可，这段对话中有很多非常有用的短语，能帮你在购物时
better price when you shop, right?
拿到更好的价格，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So the first one we have is, can you give me a better deal?
第一个短语是：能给我便宜点吗？
Can you give me a better deal?
能给我便宜点吗？
So if I'm shopping and something is too expensive, I would use this sentence with the shopkeeper.
所以如果我在购物时东西太贵，我会对店主用这句话。
Yeah.
是的。
So you might say, hey, this is out of my price range.
所以你可以说，嘿，这超出了我的预算。
Could you give me a better deal?
你能给我一个更好的价格吗？
Can you give me a better deal?
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
We have some examples of can you give me a better deal?
我们有一些关于“你能给我一个更好的价格吗？”的例子。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
I really like this shirt, but it's too expensive.
我真的很喜欢这件衬衫，但它太贵了。
Can you give me a better deal?
你能给我一个更好的价格吗？
Example two.
例子二。
Can you give me a better price on this car?
这辆车你能给我一个更好的价格吗？
I really don't have that much money.
我真的没有那么多钱。
So you can see here that you can say, can you give me a better deal?
所以你可以看到，你可以说，你能给我一个更好的价格吗？
Or can you give me a better price?
或者你能给我一个更好的价钱吗？
All right.
好的。
Let's take a look at the next phrase.
我们来看下一个短语。
That's still more than I wanted to spend.
那还是超出了我的预算。
So if the seller suggests a really high price, you can say.
所以如果卖家报了一个很高的价格，你可以说。
That's still more than I wanted to spend.
那还是超出了我的预算。
So basically, you're telling the shopkeeper.
所以基本上，你在告诉店主。
Still too expensive.
还是太贵了。
You still don't want to spend that much.
你还是不想花那么多钱。
All right.
好的。
Let's take a look at our last phrase.
我们来看最后一个短语。
That's my last offer.
这是我的最后报价。
Now, this could work both ways.
这个说法可以双向使用。
It could be the shopkeeper that's telling you that.
可能是店主在告诉你。
That's my lowest price.
这是最低价了。
Right.
对。
Or you could say, that's my last offer.
或者你可以说，这是我的最后报价。
That's my highest price if you are buying it.
如果你是买家，那就是你能出的最高价。
Right.
对。
Because sometimes when you're bargaining, the shopkeeper will say, all right, what's
因为有时候在讨价还价时，店主会说，好吧，你的报价是多少？
your best offer?
你最低多少钱？
How much will you pay?
你愿意付多少钱？
A hundred dollars.
一百美元。
That's my final offer.
这是我的最终报价。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好吧。
So we've looked at a lot of great phrases and words and now you're ready to bargain
我们已经看了很多很棒的短语和单词，现在你准备好讨价还价了。
and also listen to this dialogue for the third time.
并且第三次听这段对话。
And then we'll come back and talk some more.
然后我们会回来再聊一些。
Hello.
你好。
May I help you?
有什么需要帮忙的吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
This is really nice.
这个真不错。
How much is it?
多少钱？
That one is $150.
那个是150美元。
$150?
150美元？
What about this other one over here?
那这边这个呢？
That's $140.
那个是140美元。
That's a bit out of my price range.
这有点超出我的预算。
Can you give me a better deal?
能给我便宜点吗？
This is an exclusive design by Da Marco.
这是达·马可的独家设计。
It's a bargain at that price.
这个价格已经很划算了。
Well, I don't know.
嗯，我不确定。
I think I'll shop around.
我想我再逛逛。
Okay.
好吧。
How about $100?
100美元怎么样？
That's still more than I wanted to spend.
那还是比我预想的多。
What if I take both dresses?
如果我两条裙子都要呢？
Okay.
好吧。
I can give you a special discount just because you seem like a nice person.
我可以给你一个特别折扣，因为你看起来是个好人。
$190 for both.
两条一共190美元。
I don't know.
我不确定。
It's still a bit pricey.
还是有点贵。
Thanks anyway.
不过还是谢谢你。
Okay.
好吧。
My final price.
我的最终价格。
$100 for both.
两条100美元。
That's two for the price of one and that's my last offer.
这是买一送一，而且是我的最后报价。
Great.
太好了。
You caused a deal.
你谈成了一笔交易。
All right.
好吧。
In Canada, it's not really common to bargain, right?
在加拿大，讨价还价并不常见，对吧？
No.
不常见。
It really isn't.
确实不常见。
Even when you go to the market to buy fruits and vegetables, it's very, very rare to bargain
即使你去市场买水果蔬菜，也很少会讨价还价。
with a shopper.
和摊主讨价还价。
How about in Ecuador?
厄瓜多尔呢？
No.
不。
In Ecuador, you definitely bargain.
在厄瓜多尔，你肯定会讨价还价。
Really?
真的吗？
Well, if you go to the mall, for example, or if you go to a supermarket, of course,
嗯，如果你去商场或超市，当然不会讨价还价。
you wouldn't really bargain.
你通常不会讨价还价。
Unless maybe you go to a small store or you go to one of the local markets, then it's
除非你去小商店或当地市场，那时讨价还价就更常见了。
more common to bargain.
更常见的是讨价还价。
You have to because people expect you to bargain.
你必须讨价还价，因为人们期待你这么做。
Really?
真的吗？
In many countries in the world, bargaining is almost like an art.
在世界许多国家，讨价还价几乎是一门艺术。
Yeah, that's true.
是的，没错。
Actually, Marco, you are an excellent bargainer, aren't you?
实际上，马可，你是个很会讨价还价的人，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
I've been known to bargain with the shopkeepers.
大家都知道我会和店主讨价还价。
I've been known to bargain a little bit with the shopkeepers and helping out.
大家都知道我会和店主讨价还价，帮帮忙。
A little bit.
一点点。
I mean, you've got better prices than I can even imagine getting.
我是说，你能拿到比我预想中更好的价格。
Yeah.
是的。
That's a good story.
那是个好故事。
Maybe we'll get JP to go to our comment section and tell you about that.
也许我们会让JP去评论区告诉你这件事。
Yeah.
是的。
So we want to know about your countries.
所以我们想知道你们国家的情况。
Is it common to bargain?
讨价还价常见吗？
Do you really do it?
你真的会讨价还价吗？
Is it okay?
这合适吗？
Or when is it okay?
或者什么时候合适？
Yes.
是的。
Tell us.
告诉我们。
Visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Tell us about your country's bargaining customs and also leave your questions there for us.
告诉我们你们国家的讨价还价习俗，并在那里留下你们的问题。
Exactly.
没错。
We'll be there to answer them.
我们会在那里回答。
But until then, we've got to go.
但在那之前，我们得走了。
So, bye.
那么，再见。
And don't forget to like and subscribe.
别忘了点赞和订阅。